[Music]
Heat. Hey. Hey.
Hey.
[Music]
Heat. Heat.
Good evening and good day everybody and
welcome back to the Ask Abijit show I
just concluded my first live stream of
geio strategy with uh with Abijit Java
in case you have watched it thank you
very much and I'm sure many of you have
come to this live stream from that one
and maybe you have questions so I'm
happy to take your questions before I do
that let me see who all is there on the
live chat today with us over here so I
can see Baba Abhijit Chava I can see
geopolitical Dubai from Indor Amisha
Mishra is back hello Mr. 88s Raja Akash
Kumar Sini SS Somi Jane Kumar Kanishk
Arind Das Bupan Ba uh Prashant Bharat
Sika Priyanchi Sudatan Nagarwal only
gems Kulip Johan Niha Sharma Ankita Bat
first Anand Paynit Singh Kurana Vidi
Miar Sanatani Balak Deepika Karnesh
Kuraj Anant Chandak Sonia Singha
Navin Saiuri, Vimla Chri, Janavi,
Tinasekar, Anonymous, Feminist Slayer,
Space Striker, Niha, Senu, Nimish,
Gupta, Davic, Shrian, Beat Brawlers,
Anit again, Da Janavi, Crazy Brain,
Nirupan, Rayquel, Rquill,
Mi07,
Sepk, Rishies, Das Gupta, Sarab, Sharma,
Hitend,
Takur Gojo Mr. Bin Salman 786 Mloin
uh Abi Chandel anonymous space striker
Shubam Bosle Suya Singh Prime Somi Jane
Anu Diptas Abimmany Takur the DKin DKT
and so many other people as Minor
Rohan and so on. Thank you so much for
being on the live stream. And first of
all, let me thank uh okay, who all do we
have? Let's take some let's begin with
some questions. I will take as many as I
can. This will be a roughly 60-minute
live stream. It will not be very long,
but I'm going to have another one
tomorrow. I'm going to be doing doing
five ask live streams this week. So, I'm
going to curtail the time to about 1
hour. Okay. Uh Ratik P says, "What's
Trump's golden doom project all about?"
I am not sure. I haven't heard of it.
So, so many events are happening right
now. Let's quickly Google it. What is
Trump's Golden Dome Project? Yeah, let's
quickly Google it. Google it. Uh, Golden
Dome Project. What is
it? It's a missile defense system. Okay.
It's a proposed missiles missile defense
system. Multi-layer defense system for
the US. Well, I think they're learning
the the lessons of the various wars. So,
it's a proposed multi-layered missile
defense system for the US. Okay. Kumar
Kanisheska says, "How many no how do
goats in barren volcanic island in India
the barren island India how are they
able to survive there and how do they
exist after after several intense
volcanic eruptions? Can it help to
understand how an ancient animals
survived and evolved in the misosoic
era? Look, Baron Island is an active
volcano. As far as I know, there are two
active volcanoes that I know of in
India. One is Narokandam and one is
Baron Island. So Baron Island is not the
kind of volcano that spews immense
amounts of lava and pyrolastic flows and
all that on on a daily basis. It's kind
of active. Sometimes there's a lava flow
here and there. It's nothing. I I can't
remember the last time there was a
serious eruption over there. So as long
as there is no serious eruption, you can
have life that exists, life forms that
exist on the island. So goats live there
and whenever there's an eruption they'll
move out of the way, move to safety and
there's never been an eruption that has
blanketed the entire island and wiped
everything out. So that's why they
they're able to survive. Uh this is
unlike humans. We humans we construct
buildings and make up make up entire
civilizations and
that doing that on on a volcanic island
can be dangerous because it can it can
disrupt normal activity. So that's why
humans don't prefer to live on such
islands or or in regions close to uh
active volcanoes. Well, in Italy we have
some like Vizuvius and Sicily sorry
Ethna which erupted today. But animals
can can survive very easily and they
don't have buildings to live in. So even
if there's a lava flow and there's some
damage, it doesn't make any difference
to them. So yeah, they are able to
survive because of these regions because
of these reasons. Only Jeem says why are
Hindus not taught their religion? It's
because the education system has decided
that we are we should not be taught our
religion and that's one of the biggest
issues we have in the in the country.
The the education system is rotten. It
has it's been taken over by the lefties,
the communists. They have a strangle
hold on the academic system, the
education system and they have ensured
that we are not taught our culture. We
are the only country, only civilization
in which you don't teach kids your your
culture. So obviously they'll grow up
dassinated. The objective is to destroy
and eradicate Indian culture, religion
and
civilization.
Kaneshkumar Kaneshka says, "Is it true
that the fungi eat that the
fungus is eating the elephant foot
structure in Chernobyl? If yes, then it
can be possible that life may have
originated in space eating radiation."
Well, um, there are certain fungi that
are thriving apparently in the Chernobyl
in in the remains of the Chernobyl
nuclear power plant. I'm not sure if if
if there's a fungus that's eating the
elephant foot structure, which is
essentially the molten nuclear core, the
reactor core, right? uh but uh I believe
there are there are these funguses that
these fungi that are present on all the
walls of the control room and other
parts of the of the nuclear uh power
plant. Nobody goes there but you can
sometimes go there very briefly wearing
protective equipment can take pictures
and see what what's going on you know
routine checkups checks of the of the of
the of the um power plant and people who
went there that way that way have found
that there is black fungus that's that's
growing on the walls and it is
completely impervious to radiation
radiation doesn't affect it so even
today if you go to the Chernobyl nuclear
power plant it's a highly radioactive
zone humans any person who goes there
without protection is going to get
cancer almost guaranteed right but this
fungus is thriving there maybe it's it's
uh it's absorbing the energy the photons
and uh maybe it's it's growing because
of that I'm not sure what the biological
biochemical mechanism is uh but the
fungus is thriving in chronome I don't
think it's eating the elephant foot
structure but it's thriving um so yeah
it's an example of very rapid evolution
so fungi are very primitive organisms
compared to human beings, right? So,
they are able to adapt very quickly.
Their their genome is much smaller than
ours. So, is it possible that life may
have originated in space eating
radiation? Anything's possible. Life
possibly could have originated in space.
It's called the
panspermia
theory. Right. Next question. Sergeant
Skylin says, "Russia is willing to give
a full transfer of technology for the
SU57E.
What's my opinion on this? My opinion is
that it's very interesting and it's very
if if if it's a genuine full technology
transfer offer, then we should close our
eyes and take it or rather not close our
eyes. Maybe we should evaluate and
examine it very very thoroughly. But if
it is a genuine full transfer of
technology, I mean, come on. Of of
course we should we should take it. Um
it's it's look, I'm not sure how good or
how bad the aircraft is. It's a fifth
generation fighter plane. Uh I'm sure
it's not fully uh stealth equipped, but
I think it's a significant technological
leap over anything we have
currently and I'm sure it's uh at
least comparable to the the the the
qualities of the F-35, right? Uh so I
think if it's a genuine offer of full
technology transfer, we should certainly
certainly take it at least build 100 in
India at least minimum. Uh but the
question is is there a transfer of
technology of the jet engine as well? If
that's the case then it's even more
interesting and then we should even then
we should say yes even quicker. The
thing is we have the money the funds in
India. It's not like we have a shortage
of money. We are the fourth no the third
largest economy fourth largest economy
right in the world. So we have the funds
why not deploy the
funds acquire the technology buy it. If
the Russians are offering it buy it. So
I think they should take it if it's a
genuine full technology transfer
offer. Honey says aliens come and ask
you to take me to your your leader. What
do you do? I'll say all right. I'll take
you to Mr. Modi. That's what I'll do.
What what else can I do? Zishan Gaming.
Thank you, sir. Uh how significant is
Ukraine's recent drone strikes on
Russian bases and infrastructure? How
does this change security against drone
strikes and Russia's what's Russia's
reaction going to be like? Does this
change the the chance for
peace? The drone strikes that that
Ukraine conducted yesterday. They are
incredibly monumentally significant.
It's it's this is a piece of military
history we have seen. Russia looks like
Russia has been caught napping. Looks
like a monumental intelligence failure
on on the part of Russia, right? And uh
it looks like the Ukrainians have been
planning this for more than a year and a
half. Looks like Trump was never told
about this. Looks like Trump has been
caught completely unawares. And this
uh is going to make the world take
Ukraine way more seriously than before.
It's going to world is going to make the
world take Zalinsky way more seriously
than before. The guy means business now,
right?
He's
determined. Um, now the drone strikes on
more than which which seem to have
destroyed more than 40
uh strategic bombers of Russia. That's a
significant number. It's like 20 30% of
Russia's um uh strategic bomber fleet.
That is significant. So, it's not going
to Russia's capabilities, but
this is a significant blow to Russia's
military cap
capabilities. Uh, and it's going to have
a very significant reaction from Russia.
Russia will now scramble to move its
assets as far away from Ukraine as
possible, maybe to the Russian far
east. Russia Russia's military
establishment may be in some sort of a
panic right now because what Ukraine has
achieved is incredible. They have struck
at Russian assets thousands of
kilometers within Russian territory.
Incredible. This is a gamecher for
warfare, right? Um so now what's the
world is going to sit up and notice
this. Look at how drones can be used. I
mean in the three-day war with Pakistan,
operation Sindur, we used various kinds
of drones, loitering drones and kami
kazi dru and all and so on. The
Pakistanis used various kinds of drones.
Maybe 1,500 drones were launched in
India and those were shot down. But now
look at this how drones can be
used. This is going to open up a
Pandora's box for governments. I think
it is going to be one thing that could
happen soon is that governments may may
soon ban private possession of FPV
drones. Today content cre creators and
movie makers and all they have these
drones which which have these cameras on
board 4K cameras and all that FPV drones
and those drones can be those are pretty
inexpensive and if you talk about Indian
rupees maybe one or two lakh rupees in
the bigger scheme of things it's pretty
inexpensive not for most Indians I
understand but um from a military
perspective it's super cheap and you can
rig the drone to to drop grenades or or
explosives or to to do a kamic as a
strike
somewhere. So I think governments will
very rapidly possibly decide to ban
private possession of drones because
imagine the
possibilities. Imagine the
possibilities. You can launch terrorist
strikes with using
drones. A nation like India with more
than 100 million illegal infiltrators
living in
India. Imagine what those what those
people can do. None of them have any
allegiance to India. None of them have
any love for India's culture,
civilization or land. They are
foreigners who are simply exploiting our
our our population and our economy. And
they'll be happy to work for Pakistan or
China. Imagine such people and you have
airports in India that are surrounded by
slums in which Bangladesh and Rohingyas
and Pakistanis and God knows what else
lives. Imagine what they can do.
terror strikes using drones. It becomes
super easy to do that. I'm sure there
are measures in place around airports
for jamming of potential drone uh
flights and all that but you know there
are always counter measures. So this is
a huge huge security threat for any any
major nation.
So yeah, there's going to be a whole
paradigm change I think in the way the
world looks at drones and and
regulates drone ownership and you and
use. Now Russia's reaction first of all
is going to be initially there would
have been a few moments of panic and
they will quickly redeploy their assets
as far away as possible from Ukraine and
they will significantly enhance the
security measures they're taking to
protect their assets.
the retaliation is going to be possibly
significant. Um, and Ukraine will maybe
face the brunt of that in the coming
days, right? Does this change the pl the
chance for
peace? It's not going to change much in
the
long-term scheme of thing things, but I
think that Russia may be tempted to now
quickly put an end to this war. They
have allowed this war to meander
forever. So maybe Russia will now decide
that we will forcefully grab more
territory and pound Ukraine more
possibly. Maybe there will be
retaliation from Ukraine because now
they have the green light from the west
to use long range strike weapons. So I
think this changes the chance for peace
significantly. Peace is way more
unlikely
now. Sonia Sa thank you very much for
become becoming a member. Appreciate
that. Rahul Lakshmanan says, "What's the
Indian government's position on the use
of AI and other advanced technologies in
the military domain?" I think India is
India's government is super enthusiastic
about the use of AI and other
technologies in the military domain. I
think India has embraced AI and
high-tech emerging technologies
wholeheartedly. We have recently uh
tested a scramjet engine. uh 1,00
seconds. That's how long the scramjet
engine was tested. That's that's a
global first. Of course, it still has to
fly, but yeah, we have gone in in the
realm of scramjet technology from a
non-contender to a frontr runner. We
have retrofitted refitted 1940s AI 1940s
bow force guns anti-aircraft guns with
21st century technology radars perhaps
AI and they now they can now
autonomously shoot down
drones and and much more. So India
has wholeheartedly embraced uh is in the
process of wholeheartedly embracing AI
and other advanced emerging
technologies. one hears that India has
directed energy weapons as well, laser
beams that can take down uh incoming
threats and so on. So yeah, India is
doing great on this. I'm I'm really
pleased to report
this. Uh Arsh Douglra says, "Does Trump
really want to sabotage the India US
partnership? Is he becoming more
anti-India day by day and he now has
invested in Pakistan's crypto industry?"
Well, Trump is that kind of a guy. No
friends, no enemies. I'll do business
with anybody. If tomorrow Osama bin
Laden turns up and has a business
proposal, I'll take it seriously. I'll
consider it. He will pose with
terrorists or former terrorists. Mr.
Al-Shara of Syria, Trump is open to
anything. Any anything goes with him.
He's a super transactional guy. He's a
super short-term guy. he has this
tendency of of compro of of perhaps
putting long-term interests on the back
burner when it comes to uh you know you
know replacing them with short-term
interests some something I can get
tangibly and quickly
um and maybe he thinks that when it
comes to a nation like India which is
not as powerful as China or Russia he
can get away with bullying India and
India will have no choice but to do what
he says
um and he has investments in Pakistan
his business empire is invested in
Pakistan which is one reason why he
would not want Pakistan to be destroyed
by India. So I don't think he wants to
sabotage the India US relationship. He
simply believes that he's just too
powerful for India to resist. So I can
bully India. I can arm press India. I
can do I can go ahead and invest in
Pakistan and and rescue Pakistan but at
the end of the day I will still get what
I want from India. That's his
calculation.
So let's see how that goes.
Yeah. Uh Rohan Sunea says, "Don't you
think that now it's high time that India
should take the AMCA 5.5 generation and
join the FrancoGerman 6.5 generation
aircraft fighter program. Japan is
offering its latest engine. See my dear
friends, please understand that France
and Germany are part of NATO.
NATO is owned by the United States. I'm
putting it very crudely, but that is
actually the truth. It's actually a
fact. NATO is owned by the US. France
and Germany are both US vasals. They are
proxies for for the US. France has a
quasi independent foreign policy. France
the India France relationship is
actually quite is it's a good
relationship. But Germany is not that
favorably inclined towards India.
Right. Um so if you join an aircraft
program which is of joint French German
FrancoGerman program I can assure you
the Americans will have their eyes and
ears and fingerprints all over the
place. In every piece of technology, in
every every chip, in every line of
software code, everywhere the Americans
will be there. If you acquire those
fighter planes and when you need to use
them, they'll not do what you want. We
have seen this. We have seen this
happening to the
Australians. Japan is a nation that's
under permanent US military occupation.
Japan's economic policy, military
policy, and foreign policy are
extensions of the US policy. The US
decides all these things. So if Japan is
see if Mr. Shinszu Abi was offering
something, we would take it seriously.
He was a nationalist and he was a friend
of India. U I don't know who's the prime
minister in Japan now. Doesn't really
matter. They're all puppets of the US.
So the only
right way forward for India is to go it
alone. If France is willing to sell jet
engine technology for a price, we should
buy it. If Russia is willing to sell jet
buy it with what does it mean to buy jet
engine technology? It means that you
should be able to manufacture 100% of
the jet engine in India without any
foreign supervision or involvement.
Which means it's a 100% indigenous
engine. That's the only offer we should
take. We cannot become part of somebody
else's military programs which will that
will end up seriously compromising our
interests. Right? So please understand
that. Okay. Mr. Sharma says how exactly
do the people bloodlines and chitham
house issue orders to every nation
today?
So the question you're asking is
how the Vatican is super influential,
right? And uh many nations in the west
look upon the pope as some kind of a
world
leader,
right? Um so it it it goes back I'm not
so what is Cham House? Let me just
quickly Google that. What's Chitham
House? Cham House. Cham House. Okay.
Yeah, the chitham house rules. I know
I've been part of those chithan. Uh I've
been part of an event that was governed
by the chitham house rules. So coming
back to the to the papacy to the pope.
Look, it's an it's a very ancient
institution. It's been super powerful in
the past. It's the institution that
destroyed the Roman Empire, the Western
Roman Empire, and it has been enscconced
in Rome ever since.
And the popes ruled Europe for more than
a thousand years. They were the most
powerful force in Europe. And the legacy
of that is that even today there could
be some remnants of power left you know
which may not be visible but it may be
there. And even today the the many most
Christian people see the pope as the
leader of their community. And and and
therefore because of this legacy this
history and the status of the pope pope
being regarded by 2 million Christians
as a world leader as a consequence of
that the Vatican seems it fit seems to
see it fit that they can you know or
issue directives and orders to various
nations and and uh negotiate with a
nation as if it's a sovereign entity and
so on. It's a consequence of this
1500700 almost year history of of uh
this
institution. Shibam says why is Japan's
AI
robot lead lost to the others? Uh Japan
was never in the AI race. They have not
been allowed to become part of the AI
race for the Americans and they have not
been allowed to develop superior you
know military grade robots by the
Americans. So that's why the Americans
control everything and that's the short
answer. Feminist Slayer says, "Do
geopolitical principles are are they
also applicable in real life like
friendship only for shared interests,
power overriding morality, self-interest
over everything?" You know, you can be
inspired by geopolitical principles, but
you can't use geopolitical principles in
in things like close family. When it
comes to family, you can't use
geopolitical principles. You know, you
can't have um power overriding morality
when it comes to family. You can't have
self-interest overriding the needs of
your family members. I mean, some people
can do that. Those are those people are
generally called
narcissists. I'm sure we all know of
you. Okay? But look, when it comes to
business interests, let's say you're an
individual, one person, not a company,
not a nation, one person. You can use
the same geopolitical principles in
business. You can use the same
geopolitical principles in politics. If
you're a politician, if you are a person
who is in a situation like you're in an
office and you're dealing with office
politics, you can use geopolitical
principles there. When it comes to close
friends, you probably should not do
that. You know, friendship is a
different thing.
uh and when it comes to family, you
should certainly should not do that
unless you're a narcissist, a
manipulator. Uh but yes, you can use
geopolitical principles in other aspects
of life. That's why especially in
business and sports. I remember about 25
years ago when Pat Buchanan was the
coach of Australia, the Australian
cricket team when Shane Ward, Ricky
Ponting, etc. used to play for
Australia. He he was very fond of
quoting Sununzu the
Chinese
strategist and uh he made it a point to
tell the world that you know I you know
I apply geopolitical and strategic
principles from the field of warfare in
sports and so on. So yeah it has
applications
everywhere. Uh geopolitical Dubis says
how did the Houthi shoot down US stealth
jets? Look the Houthis did not shoot
down the F-35. It came somehow
apparently close to being shot down or
going down for some reason. The Houthis
shot down F18 fighter planes which are
not stealthy fighter planes. Uh the F
F18 or F18 is usually used for
electronic warfare jamming and such
operations. But apparently two of them
were shot down by the Houthis. So the
Houthis seem to have good missiles, good
anti-aircraft missiles. And when you are
in range, you know, sometimes it becomes
a mathematical prob possibility, a
mathematical certainty that if you come
within a certain range of a certain
missile, you're going to get shot down
no matter what you do. Uh so yeah,
that's how the Houthis were able to
shoot down US jets, but those were not
stealth jets. So that's one amendment to
our understanding we need to make.
Cyclian Ready says, "Is it true the hate
of India is spreading by Chinese media
or is it the because of the civic sense
of our people? As a mechanical engineer
myself, how can I tackle
AI?" Okay, like at least two different
questions here.
Um, look, Chinese media is not spreading
hate of India. The Chinese media will
will talk disparagingly about India and
so on but they don't spread hatred of
Indian culture of or Indian traditions
or Indian people. It's the western media
that does this. uh they spread what can
be reasonably called Hindu phobia and
they spread the narrative that Indian
people are
extremely I don't know what what are the
stereotypes they try to portray that
Indians uh smell like curry Indians
don't smell well Indians uh um are
disorderly perhaps and uh we don't have
toilets in India that the same old
stereotypical
uh jibes you know they they use certain
offensive terms, derogatory terms for
Indians and so on. This is the western
media. Now it's not look the BBC won't
do that. They will do it way more
subtly. They will never use derogatory
words but they will subtly reinforce you
know false stereotypes and and so on.
And uh if there's a whole infrastructure
of media you know from the prestigious
outlets to the the pedestrian outlets
and then you have social media trolls.
So all of that together is deployed
against India. So it's not the Chinese
media. The Chinese media is not very
friendly towards India for sure. Uh but
the Chinese media doesn't spread hatred
of Indian culture towards Indian culture
and Indian people as far as I have seen
personally. I may be wrong. In case I'm
wrong, please do point out where it is
and I'm I'll I'll learn something from
that. Yeah. So it's mainly the West that
hates India. Why do they hate India?
Because we are the last surviving
polytheistic culture. We're the oldest
surviving civilization in the world and
we still haven't been broken by the
west. How dare we survive? And that's
the that's why they hate us. Uh as a
mechanical engineer, how can I tackle
AI? Look, AI is a big challenge. Right
now, nobody can see it, but in a few
years, most pedestrian jobs, most entry-
levelvel jobs are going to be replaced
by AI. It's
coming. As a mechanical engineer, I'm
not sure what you can do about AI. AI is
in the realm of software and so on. Um
but I'm sure that there's going to be an
AI influence in mechanical engineering
also. So what is what comes under
mechanical engineering? It's machinery
and stuff like that, right? Machines
that build machines and um things like
that. Well, you know, AI is is going to
be part of that process also, especially
in the in design and AI will be uh
integrated and married with robotics. So
you're going to have AI equipped robots
doing a lot of the work that that
historically people would do, you know,
and so on. So the people who will
survive the the coming of
AI are the people
who what well most people will be
unfortunately replaced. The people who
will survive and thrive are the ones who
think
differently. Are the ones who see every
problem as an
opportunity. The people who will thrive
in the AI era are the ones
who
question, the ones who innovate and the
ones who build something, create
something. These are the these are the
qualities we need to have. So AI is
coming in every sector and if we if you
are you are somebody who sees this as a
tool you can use to do something bigger
and create something better then you
will be among the few who will survive
in that and you and then you will be in
control of multiple AI employees. You'll
be an AI manager and then imagine
how powerful that will make you and how
much you'll be able to create with that.
So yeah that's a
deal. Abijit Sher Rajan says what
lessons can we learn from Japan's
isolation era? See Japan became very
insular, very isolationist for about
more than 500 years. Um and because of
that they lost contact with the world.
They were not able to keep up with what
was happening in the world. And when
they first came in contact with the
Europeans, the Europeans already had way
more advanced sailing methods and
techniques and ships and they understood
navigation much better than than the
Japanese. They had uh more advanced
weapons than the Japanese. So if you
become isolated, if you become an
insular nation, you get cut off from
what's happening in the rest of the
world. You are not aware of the
developments. You may not be able to
benefit from new technologies that may
be emerging. You may not get the
intelligence about threats that exist
out out there. Uh you may not get access
to new knowledge that may be circulating
across the world. Um and so on. And if
you become insular and isolationist,
then um you become scared of everybody.
You think everybody is a monster, right?
That sort of thing. So multiple lessons
can be learned from Japan's isolation
era.
Um and this eventually was ended by
Japan. It was ended by the Japanese
bureaucracy, not by the Japanese
emperors. That was the period of the
Maji restoration in which they said that
we will
end all our isolationist practices. We
will end our long-standing traditions.
We will destroy the samurai and shogunit
system. We will try and stamp out
Buddhism and so on. That didn't quite
work. But yeah that that turned Japan
into an imperial power and that was
eventually the cause of its defeat in
the second world war. So they had
multiple centuries of isolation. Then
they tried to reverse it at at a break
neck break neck
pace and uh the the end result wasn't
very great for Japan.
Hardik Jooshi says, "How can we solve
India's problem of quality of life,
depression, economic gaps? It's mostly
the Amani Adani pulling the economy up.
How to minimize the gap? How to minimize
the gap? We need to become a
manufacturing power. We need the only
way you can provide so many jobs to
people is by becoming a major
manufacturing power by replacing China.
The West is thinking beyond China. They
want to pull out of China. So India is
the only nation that can u provide
manufacturing at scale. So we have the
potential, we have the population, we
have all of that but we need to um work
on the ease of doing business. We need
to work on land acquisition on all that.
If we become a major manufacturing
power, everybody will have a job, right?
And then the quality of life goes up
when everybody has a job. uh when
everybody uh when everybody starts
earning more money and then the GDP per
capita goes up and the rise of the GDP
per capita number is intrinsically
related to quality of life. So right now
India's GDP per capita let's say it's
$2,000 let's say but China is $10,000
$11,000. So their GDP per capita is
about five and a half six times more
than us. So then their quality of life
is you could reliably say is about five
or six times better than us ours. That's
how it is. Uh so the government needs to
implement reforms big reforms in
uh uh in investing in in the ease of
doing business uh in welcoming foreign
investors uh and so on. And another
thing which needs to happen in India is
is uh we need to put an end to
corruption. One of the biggest reasons
why there is such poor quality of life
in India cities. I'm sure there are some
cities which are wonderful, better than
Venice. I'm sure there must be some. But
overall it is said that the average city
has very terrible infrastructure and
quality of life and overall it's it's
terrible. Uh so that's that the cause of
that is corruption. Okay to put it very
um
succinctly so India needs to fix that
issue the corruption issue it is alleged
that it's everywhere and it's what it's
the system it is the part of the system
that runs the Indian
um machinery right so that that that's
what needs to happen so India needs to
become a major manufacturing power um we
need big
reforms in the economy
in ways of doing business and we need to
start a war on corruption. If we do
these things, a lot of these problems
will eventually be solved. Depression is
is is a consequence of very poor living
standards and a lack of hope in the
future. Right? So all these
uh things will will address the
problems. Okay. Hush the says Modu Chanu
leadership compared to Shingishis Khan.
What is Modu
Chanu
Modu Modu Chanu? What is Modu
Chanu? Oh wow. Shau well
well I haven't studied this part of
history. I haven't studied Shau history.
Interesting.
Modu Chanu ruled from
209 to 174 BC. Fascinating. He was a
military leader under his father Tuman
and later Chanu of the Shunyu Empire
based on the Mongolian plateau. So I
have spoken about the Shyu a lot of
times but I have not studied their
history. They are the tribal
confederation that
displaced the
Kusans from their homeland in the Tarim
River basin region and the Kusans were
forced to flee westwards and southwards.
They ended up displacing the Skithians
who were living in Gandhar and they the
Smithians invaded India as a as a
consequence and about a century and a
half later the Kushans themselves in
invaded India. All of this was triggered
by the Sha newu expansion and apparently
Mulanu was one of the great leaders. So
I haven't studied his life history but
fascinating I I learned a new name today
and maybe sometime if I in the future if
I have the time I
may read up a little bit about Muduch
Chanu so I can't compare the two because
I haven't I I've studied only Chingish
Khan. So but yeah very
interesting. Ankita says, "What will
happen to Ukraine now after operation
spiderweb on Russia?" So, operation
spiderweb was what happened yesterday.
The unprecedented Ukrainian drone
strikes on Russian military
infrastructure destroyed more than 40
aircraft apparently and uh attacked a
naval base apparently. There were
submarines there apparently. Uh the full
details will take time to come out. It's
still an evolving situation. What will
happen to Ukraine
now? Uh Russia may decide. There's a
high probability that the Russia now
decides that we're going to end the war
this
season. We will achieve our military
objectives, whatever they are,
territorial objectives, regime change
objectives, whatever the objectives are
in the next few months. There's a high
prob probability that that happens and
that's something I covered just now in
the previous liveream
geostrategy. So I think there's going to
be a a significant Russian retaliation
against Ukraine.
U Russia is most likely going to pound
Ukraine with missile and drone strikes.
It's going to most likely target
Ukraine's strategic infrastructure,
military military infrastructure,
possibly
cities and maybe there'll be a
significant offensive in the Sunumi
region in the in in some other parts of
Ukraine as well. in in the Sunumi region
the there's a significant uh massing of
more than 50,000 Russian troops. So that
may come into play soon. So I think
there's going to be a significant
escalation of the war right now and
maybe if Russia gets gets their way they
may end the war in a few months and
obviously the West will try their best
to not allow this to happen. But the
most likely scenario is escalation
significant escalation next 7 to 30
days. significant
exclation. Betrine says, "Are there any
any physics theories of of everything
that you find convincing? Weinstein's
geometric unity or Langan's
CTMU." Look, there is no theory of
everything right now that provides all
the answers.
A theory of everything has to unify
quantum mechanics or quantum field
theory with the geometric dynamics which
is Einstein's general relativity. It
essentially has to give us a way of
quantizing
gravity. And right now there's no theory
of everything that does this. I haven't
really studied Eric Weinstein's
geometric unity. I haven't had the time
to do that. But uh I as far as I know
there's no theory that gives gives us
gives us the answers. If there was a
theory of everything that would actually
be able to quantize gravity that would
be I mean it would be earth shaking
news. There's no such thing. We are
nowhere closer to understanding gravity
in 2025 than we were in the year
2000. So yeah it's it's a it's a period
of stagnation. It's a long period of
stagnation in theoretical physics in
fundamental physics. The stagnation
began in 1979 around 1980. The last big
advance big theoretical breakthrough
that was proven by experimental
evidence. The last such breakthrough was
uh Alan Good's theory of
inflation. Since then there's nothing.
Physics has hit a brick wall and that's
where we
are. Dish Shukla says you work in so
many areas. I do have many interests but
I don't know what to do. I'm 27 stuck in
corporate life. I want to travel and do
something myself.
Advice.
Look, my
advice is
this. You want to travel. You want to do
something for yourself, something that
that is in line with your interests, but
you're not able to do it because you're
stuck in the corporate world. And why
are you stuck in the corporate world?
because that's where the money comes
from. And if you get out of the cor
corporate world, maybe you won't have an
income, right? That's that's the issue.
What is the source of freedom of
personal freedom? It's
wealth. So my advice to you is find a
way to become wealthy. Now that's a very
very very generic advice.
Uh it's it's not possible to become
genuinely rich, genuinely wealthy
working a corporate job. But you can if
you if you play the game right, you can
have significant savings by the time
you're 30, 35 perhaps. Then if you are
good at investing or something, you can
turn that into some form of wealth. And
if you really are if you really have
iron in you then after the 9 to5 we can
do a 5 to 5 to 12 and do something on
the side some kind of side business or
something you know um there are multiple
possibilities multiple avenues like that
the main problem you are facing is that
you are financially stuck to the
corporate job. So you need to find a way
to solve that problem.
If you want to travel, if you want to do
something else, you're going to need
funds. You're going to need money.
You're going to need wealth. So, my
advice is become wealthy. Find some way
based on your strengths and your
uh in your characteristics. Find a way
to get wealthy to become
wealthy. All the best they wish.
Rick and Jen says are there any
differences as to how the US acts as a
superpower and how India is to act as a
superpower in let's say Ashok or Chundra
Gupta's times okay what's the definition
of the term
superpower my definition is this a
superpower is a nation that can
intervene
militarily anywhere on the planet at
about 60 minutes
notice in the 20th century There were
two superpowers, the USSR and the US.
Both could intervene militarily anywhere
in the world at 60 minutes notice. Today
there's only one, the US that can do
that. China can't do it. Russia can't do
it. India can't do it. My my question is
this. Was India a
superpower in Ashok's time or Chad
Gupta's time? Could India intervene
militarily anywhere on the planet at 60
minutes notice? India could not. Nobody
could. So there were no superpowers back
then. There were empires and we were a
major
empire. We were the richest empire
during the Morian Morian era and uh we
had a significant hedgemony over the
region. I'm sure I'm sure we did not use
that but we were a net significantly
massive net exporter of culture and I'm
sure we had influence we had military
relations with Greece by the way an
alliance with the Greece with the Greeks
with the Seucid Empire and all that. So
India was not a hegemonic power overall.
India was a very benevolent power. India
did not try to ever invade Persia. India
did not ever in during the Morian era.
We never tried to fight with the
Persians. They were our cousins, right?
Why fight them? One thing is very
interesting in history. Persia India
never fought. The Persians never
launched the kind of invasion on India
that they they were repeatedly launching
towards the
west. Never. Never. the thought never
arose right because it's a family it's a
blood relationship
um so India was not a hgemonic power
India did not arm twist other nations
India did not plunder other nations
India did not occupy other other nations
territory and so on so it's very
different from the way US acts today the
US physically occupies some nations
militarily Japan South Korea Italy
Germany find out and it uses other
nations as proxies by creating these
these intricate alliances NATO EU it
uses other proxies as proxies to to
expand to to to project power
historically the US used France as a
proxy to project power in in a in
various parts of Africa and so
on so that's the kind of power the US is
that's the kind of empire the US is it's
a hegemonic empire there are two kinds
of empires two types of empires if you
read Dr. Edward Lutwak's book the grand
strategy of the Roman Empire which was
written probably in the 1970s he defines
there are that there are two kinds of of
empires a hegemonic empire and an empire
that's based on occupation on on
military occupation on territorial
occupation. So if you want to occup to
to base your power on territorial
occupation of other nations that is
very energy intensive takes a lot of
your resources to militarily have foot
boots on the ground but if you can do it
hegemonically by creating vasal states
you never have to put boots on the
ground you never have to spend so much
money and resources so the US is that
kind of empire it's kind of balancing
two things but it's mostly
hegemonic and it It occupies militarily
only a few countries. India has never
been that sort of an entity. So very
different. Bimosha Kandel, thank you
very much for your contribution. Really
appreciated. You didn't you didn't ask a
question but you contributed. Thank you
very much. Thank you. Vive Singh says
India's government has been pushing back
some Bangladesh issues. How do you think
the Bangladesh government will react and
what should be our counter? I think the
Bangladesh government may try to resist
some of this.
I've heard some some dissatisfaction
coming from the Bangladeshi government
about India pushing Bangladeshes back
into Bangladeshi territory. Um my so
what will Bangladesh do? It depends on
the scale at which we are pushing back
the illegal infiltrators. If we are
pushing back 100 200 a
day, it may evict it may even a certain
kind of response. But if we are pushing
back 10,000 a day, that will have a
totally different kind of response. See,
we most likely have about a 100 million
Bangladeshes squatting on Indian
territory. 100 million. Let's say you
want to send them back in 10 years. That
means that you have to send back 10
million a
year,
right? So every month essentially every
36 days you to send back 1
million 10
lakhs which means every 3 and a half
days you to send back one
lakh which means every day you have to
send back
30,000. If we are doing
that, there's going to be a very very uh
severe uh set of complaints coming from
Bangladesh. They will go and cry to the
world that the Indians are flooding us
with refugees or whatever and this is a
humanitarian crisis and so on. And then
the world gets involved in this. They
say it's a humanitarian disaster and so
on and they'll then want to accuse India
of human rights violations and uh so on
so forth that sort of thing.
uh so it depends on the scale at which
we are pushing people back. right now if
you're put pushing 100 200 500 a day um
the Bangladeshes are already kind of
complaining the the fact is that
Bangladesh can do nothing about this if
we decide to push everybody back they
have to accept those people it's not
like they can resist us right uh but
yeah this is an evolving situation I
hope we send every Bangladeshi back
every illegal Bangladeshi back the ones
who have come to India legally please
feel free to be here legally we have
nothing against
We have an issue with the
illegals. Every person who has entered
India legally is welcome to stay as long
as they are legally allowed. No issue
with that. So I think it's high time we
we do
that. Um Bimar Shaandal
says has the world war started can b can
give brief info chances of Russia to use
nukes. Give me your opinion. Is this the
beginning of world war? I hope yesterday
there was talk of World War II starting.
So after this operation spider web, the
Ukrainian strikes that destroyed
allegedly more than 40 Russian
long-range strategic bombers, there was
speculation that Russia may use may
resort to the use of tactical nuclear
weapons, not strategic weapons, but
tactical nukes, low yield, kiloton yield
nuclear warheads.
Um it's not happened and thankfully it's
not happened. I'm I'm glad it's not
happened. We don't want that.
Um so look, world war means US and
Russia are fighting. That's a world war.
If the US and China are fighting, that's
not a world war. Only US, Russia, them
fighting makes it world war. And then
there's a very very very significant
chance of nuclear escalation. So what's
the chances of Russia using nukes? I
think the chances are low right now.
They have been bit hit very hard.
They've lost about 20 30% of the
strategic bomber fleet, which is a
disaster, but they still have about 70%
roughly of their bomber strategic bomber
fleet. And uh they're going to secure
that now very very seriously. And
they're going to most likely hit Ukraine
hard in retaliation. I don't think they
will use nukes on Ukraine. Doesn't make
sense from my perspective. they can hit
Ukraine hard using conventional
means and without the need to use
nuclear weapons. So I don't think this
is the beginning of World War II. not
yet and I hope it never happens but this
is not the stage but Ukraine is now
becoming a more significant more
pronounced flash point and uh especially
given what happened yesterday and the
the west having given Ukraine the
permission to use long range weapons
that can strike deep within Russian
territory I think the the Ukrainians are
going to start using
that and in case there they use let's
say German weapons to strike Russia deep
inside Russia Russia may strike at
Berlin. So if that
happens then we are a step closer to
World War II because then the US may
feel feel compelled because of NATO uh
commitments to defend Germany and so on.
So if Ukraine uses longrange weapons
against Russia that the Germans and the
Americans have given then Russia will
most possibly strike at Germany in
German territory. that brings into
action the NATO clauses that an attack
on one member state of NATO is an attack
on all of them and then that we are
closer to World War II. So I think it
depends on what Ukraine does
now. Vidi says what's the best veg
protein source which is not high carbs?
Uh paneer. Uh paneer is dense. It is it
has way more protein per
uh than milk obviously per same volume
but it is it is high in fat as well but
it has next to no carbs. So when it
comes to protein sources with with which
are veg but low carbs, I think it's milk
and paneer only. Maybe tofu also
perhaps. I'm not sure if tofu tofu has
carbs. I would go with paneer. And
paneer is obviously tastier than other
non-veg sources. So I would say I I
would go with
paneer. Saiti jared. Thank you very much
sir. Thank you very much. Rdra says what
will Russia react according to old or
new doctrine? I think Russia will react
by first of all moving its strategic
bomber fleet further away into its
hintterlands and secondly it's going to
react by pounding Ukraine the next few
days and Russia may decide may have
decided to end the war in the next 3 to
6 months now by by achieving their
military and political objectives. So
that's how I think Russia will react.
We're going to see a significant uptick
in the war and it's going to be a
significant escalation go in the next
week or two. That's what I see
happening. Sait ready says is it okay to
purchase electric car in 2025 in India.
Um as long as the car is good and it has
a good endurance. I mean how many
kilometers does it go between charges
and all?
I would, if I were to purchase an
electric car, I would want it to go at
least 100 km before being charged again
at least. Um, and I would I want it to
have the same performance, the same
speed, the same pickup, the same kind of
thing as a regular car. Should look good
also. If I'm paying money, good money,
then it should look good and so on. Um,
and I'm not sure which vehicles are in
the market. There are hybrid vehicles
and maybe electric vehicles also. So, it
depends on various factors and it
depends on your personal choices, but I
think it's certainly okay to purchase an
electric car if it makes sense for
you. Uh, United Alliance 14 says, "Are
you excited to play GTA 6 or the 26th of
May
2026?" Grand Theft Auto. I've never
played the game. I'm not much of a
gamer. I I was one of the guys who
bought the the brand new PlayStation 2
when it came out. You know, I had a few
games I used to play on
that. There was this game called, what
was it
called? It was something about car
crashing cars all all over the place.
Now, I played a game called Dynasty
Warriors and something some Star Wars
game also. I've never played GTA 6. Uh,
and today we don't have the PS2 anymore.
I I gave mine
away. Uh, today is a day of it's the era
of PS5 and and Xbox and all that, right?
But yeah, I've never played the game and
uh I don't have the time to game. I
would love to game again. Uh but uh
yeah, no time. So I think I'm going to
skip GTSX whenever it comes out 26th of
May
2026. Kapai developer says, "How do you
think AI, which is LLM?" First of all,
thank you for the contribution. How do
you think AI or LLM is going to shift
management in the private sector? I
notice resistance from the top
leadership to the use of AI in example
for example HR departments as for
founders how do we market look HR
folks will be the first to
resist okay and the first adopters of AI
will be the people the tech
folks not all the tech folks not the
low-level tech folks who are going to be
replaced uh the highskilled tech folks
the ones who want to innovate they will
see AI as an opportunity to innovate.
Let's leverage AI and innovate more. I
wish I had 10 employees who were like
top class coders, but I only have 10
employees who are mediocre coders. But
now, if I have AI, then I can get rid of
the mediocre coders and have top class
coding
AIs to help build and execute my vision.
Right? So it's those folks who will want
to be the early adopters of AI in any
private sector company
especially software companies and so on.
Top leadership will be happy as long as
it makes money. If you can demonstrate
to top leadership that it is a money
spinner. Oo they'll love it. They'll
love it. Look you spend so much money on
employees. You have to spend so much
time training employees when they first
come in. Then you have to monitor them.
Some are lazy. Some are demotivated,
some lack talent, some lack lack
whatever else. It's only the like 2% who
are really top top class employees,
right? And those are the ones who who
rise and become leaders. So if if you're
a founder, if you're in the top
leadership, you'll be happy with the
adoption of AI. Then you'll just need a
few people to manage the AI. So you're
going to significantly downsize in that
case while becoming more productive. The
HR departments will complain. HR folks
are
the HR folks you know how they are right
we all if you've been in the corporate
sector ever you know how HR folks are
super you
know patronizing patternalistic and so
on so forth the least productive I'm
sure there are some who are good I'm
sure there some of them contribute to
the company well and all but overall we
know how they are there are different
set of people
um so forget talking about the HR
departments once you once you have AI
employees what will HR do first of
all right uh so that's the thing so I
think once AI becomes uh a thing in
various
industries it's going to be a very
different kind of setup in every every
every
company excuse
me managers will be managing AIS teams
of AIS that's what's going to happen and
if you're a founder
then it's it's it's a great time for
you. You can uh you know uh do more
while spending less. You will just need
to have a few people who know how to
manage AIS. That's that's where we
going. That's the direction in which the
world is going. Kapay Kapay developer
says could you please expound on foiman
probes? Foiman probes are um it's it's a
theoretical thing. It's never been done.
But these are rep self-replicating
robotic probes who go to other planets
who who go to other worlds, other star
systems looking for planets that are
that are suitable for human
habitation. And uh if they find such a
planet, then they will send signals back
to humanity that you know we found this
thing, you can come and settle over
here. It's a good place for human
habitation.
And in case they they are running out of
fuel or something they can land on on
another planet which may not necessarily
be suitable for human habitation but
which will have the resources to build
more of these one no one pro
probes. So the the probe has the tools
to build more probes like itself using
raw materials from other
worlds. So it goes and lands there. It
builds more probes. The other probes
also then set out and look for more
worlds for humans to inhabit. That I
believe, if I remember correctly, is the
concept of the fun Noan probes. Very
interesting sci-fi concept. Maybe it'll
become reality someday in the future.
Literally, officer K says, "In all
honesty, why does Pakistan get away with
it? They've done several genocides,
ethnic cleansing, and war crimes. Why
does the world not react? The
world does whatever the media tells
them, thinks whatever the media tells
them to think. The media, it's all about
propaganda. It's the biggest propaganda
machine in the world. And the media
we're talking about is the western
controlled, western dominated English
speaking and western languages speaking
media. For these nations which are led
by the US, Pakistan serves a very
important role. Pakistan is very
valuable. It serves the purpose of
destabilizing India and keeping India
off balance. The west doesn't want India
to rise again after a gap of almost a
thousand years. They don't want after a
gap of about 500 years. They don't want
us to rise. They want us want us to
remain down because if we rise
historically we were the greatest
largest economy for the most part of
history they don't want us to become the
most powerful economy once again most
powerful nation once again. So that's
why you need nations like Pakistan to
keep on damaging India to keep on
bleeding and you know uh hammering away
at India and if Pakistan does that then
everything is forgiven. They will keep
quiet about what Pakistan has done to
Hindu population. They'll keep quiet
about what about what they've done what
they are doing in the process of doing
to the Baljasthan to the Pakun Pakun
people ethnic cleansings war crimes and
they will keep about Pakistan being the
world's epicenter of terrorism. They
will now say that the Sahil region is
the world's epicenter of terrorism and
so on. Pakistan gets away with it
because it it is a mercenary nation that
that offers valuable services to the
west. That's why Pakistan gets away with
it. Joy Dev Takar says Bouge awaits
veiled. Oh yes, I have seen your email.
I will respond to it as soon as I can.
Thank you. Thank you so much. Thank you.
Vid says I'm 23 with a degree in AI, no
experience. interested in bureaucracy
and serving society but failed UPSC.
People say this exams and bureaucracy is
a waste. Am I wasting potential or
should I trust my gut? Look, if it's
been if it's been a lifelong aim of
yours and if it's something that you are
passionate about, then you should
certainly follow it. But if you think
that it's but if if the reason for uh
you know pursuing the UPSC and
bureaucracy is because you think it'll
make money and all then maybe not not
the right thing. But it looks like you
are interested in bureaucracy because
you want to serve
society. In which case it's okay to
spend maybe two three years trying for
the UPSC. So the UPSC exam has a very
very low probability of success. Only
about a thousand people get through and
millions millions are competing for it,
right? Millions take the sit for the
exam. So the probability of success is
very low first of all. But yeah, some of
some people are super intelligent and
they are really good at this. So maybe
if you're one of them, you can try for a
year or two, but don't spend 7 8 years
of your life chasing this. Try it for a
year or two, but you have a degree in
AI, which means you have some skills.
You may not have
experience, but you could leverage that
too. And you could serve society using
AI as well. Uh so I would not say you
you're wasting your potential. You're
still very young. You're 23. I think you
can afford to spend a year or two maybe
even three years at most I would say uh
pursuing your dream of uh being a
bureaucrat and serving society by by
doing that. So but don't waste too many
years of your life doing that two three
years at at most I would say then you
need to look at other options and life
gives you lots of options. So yeah, all
the best sir. I'm so glad you want to
serve society and I hope that you get to
serve society to the fullest of your
potential in whichever field uh works
out for you whether it's bureaucracy or
or something else. So all the best
sir. Suman Vikran Panda says did do you
think the CIA conceals info to its
president? Look the US president gets a
daily intelligence brief. It's given by
the CIA, the FBI and the director of the
national intelligence services which is
Tulsi Gabbard. So Tulsiabad or some
minions under her will collect
information from all the services and
synthesize it and give the info to the
president. Now you can't give all the
information to your president. You can
only give the most high impact
developments and so on that sort of
daily briefing to your president. So
that way it's very easy to conceal info
if you want
to. Uh Jot Joti Viri says what's the
situation of Indian students in the US?
Are students being kicked out for giving
political speeches or are they being
affected at random? Look, students have
no business giving political speeches
and becoming politically active in a
country where you're not a citizen. If
you do that, you should be kicked
out. If you are there as a student, it
means most likely your parents are
paying money, lot of money for that.
Don't waste the money and the time that
you've been given and the opportunity
you've been given by indulging in
political activism. Get your study and
and acquire a degree. That's
it. Uh so first of all, that's what I
have to say. That's the first thing I
have to say. Uh secondly, uh there is
increased scrutiny on foreign foreign
students under the Trump regime, right?
uh they're going to scrutinize all the
visa applications like they're going to
do it like uh much more seriously than
before. Uh they're going to look into
every student's past and the social
media accounts and what they've been
saying and all and maybe some students
could be deported because of that. So I
think it's it's not a very good time to
be a foreign student in the US. Uh
they're essentially going after Chinese
students primarily but who knows Indians
could be next. uh and there is a rise of
anti-Indian sentiment in the US and in
the west generally for various reasons.
So Indian students should be careful in
the US. I don't think they are being
targeted or affected at random. Right
now the Chinese are being selectively
targeted because Chinese have a history
of allegedly spying in the US and
extracting valuable information
technologies and so on. So the Americans
are going after the Chinese first but
who knows about the Indians. Maybe that
could happen to Indians as well. So I
think it's it's if you are thinking of
considering the US as a place where you
want to go for your studies, I think
it's time to kind of give it more
serious
thought. Right. Okay. Uh please stop now
uh doing the super chats because I'm
going to wrap up very soon. Um yeah, so
I'll take a few more questions.
Obviously I'll finish all the super
chats. Hush says if democracy gives
equality to to all then what will be the
scenario when AI gets elected democrat
democratically would humans accept it?
Look for AI for an AI system to get
democratically elected you're going to
need changes to the constitution and the
laws of a
country to allow an AI to stand for
election. And for those laws to be
changed in the constitution to be
amended, it means that humans will have
to do that first. Right? Which means
that humans are okay with AI coming to
power. So
logically AI can stand for election only
when humans first change the
constitutions constitution and the
laws in which case humans are okay with
it. So then humans would certainly
accept an A getting elected. See
logic. Prelt says, "What happens when
people become useless after AI comes?
What pillars may fall if India was
possibly collapsing? How universal basic
income could impact India?" Look, if
people become useless after AI comes, I
know what you mean. People get replaced,
uh jobs take away all automated and
low-skilled jobs. I mean, AI takes takes
over all the um lowskilled jobs,
lowskilled labor, uh and entry- level
jobs and all that. what what can I do?
Most people are are in such low income
uh low skill and entry- level jobs,
right? So, what do you do about that?
So, what happens when AI takes over is
that the industry the the sector the
company becomes way more productive and
makes way more money which means the
government gets way more
taxed. So, then these people who become
let's say hypothetically jobless in the
future because of AI I think the
government will have to provide for
them. There will be no other option. So
like you say universal basic
income that's that's one way of going
one one way of doing it you know um so
it's still all hypothetical but it could
happen. So maybe the government will
have to take the responsibility of
providing for the people who have been
made redundant by by artificial
intelligence systems in their various
respective uh
sectors. Uh so that's the that's the
solution that one can think of right
now.
Jagen says, "My question is how
difficult is it going to be to maintain
strategic autonomy with a non-aligned
policy? Both the US and China are have
strategic have significantly trying to
encircle India in our backyard." Okay.
Thank you. Thank you. Um we don't have a
non-alignment
policy. Don't non-alignment is a thing
of the 20th century. It was Mr. Neu's
policy and the policies of various
subsequent Indian
governments. Today we have a
multi-alignment policy. We are aligned
with everybody. We are friends with
everybody. We will engage with
everybody. We'll do business with
everybody. We'll trade with everybody.
And wherever we have strategic
alignment, we will do strategic
partnerships but not alliances with with
wherever we have strategic
convergence. So that's not
non-alignment, it's multi-alignment. and
its strategic autonomy which means that
we will not take anyone's side and we
will not take the side of the US or
China when it comes to their um their
confrontation and their adversarial
relationship. We'll stay out of it.
We'll cooperate with both as far as
possible. How difficult is it going to
be to maintain this
position? It's going to be difficult.
Trump wants India to bend over. Trump
wants India to do whatever he's asking
us to do. He wants us to have zero
tariffs to to completely open our market
to US products and if we accept that
they will say that okay now you need to
be on my side with China and you need to
impose sanctions on Russia. So we have
refused to do these things right. We are
currently engaged in trade negotiations
with the US. I don't think we're going
to give them zero zero tariff zero
tariff policy and we have we have
resisted significant US and western
pressure. um to participate in the
sanctions sanctions regime against
Russia. So it's difficult but it's
important we do this otherwise we become
a puppet just another puppet. So it's
going to be difficult. There's going to
be a lot of pressure increasingly more
pressure but it's something we have to
do. Uh the US and China are definitely
both trying to encircle us in our own
backyard. The Americans did a regime
change in Bangladesh. They turned it
into East Pakistan again and they need a
regime change in Pakistan as well in
2022 by ousting Imran Khan and getting a
puppet as as prime minister. So East and
West Pakistan are both US vasals today.
The Chinese are trying their own games
in the region. The string of pearl
strategy and so on. They're trying to
encircle us all
themselves. So it's a difficult
neighborhood for us. But we are 1.4
billion of us. So let us not be
discouraged. We will find a
way. Gor Seak says, "Is there a deep
state in India?" Because BJP top leaders
sometimes speak absolute nonsense. For
example, Mr. Modi said, "I'm
non-biological." Which gives chance to
leftists. Um, okay. I'm I'm not aware of
this non-biological thing.
Um, sometimes leaders speaks speak
leaders speak nonsense. I is I'm sure
it's it's possible that that happens
sometimes from some leaders. Um is there
a deep state in India? What does this
have to do with a deep state? Uh look
when it comes to the deep state that
people talk about of the US it is this
alleged entity this extra democratic
extra electoral extra government center
of power
uh that controls the nation allegedly
and its economy and everything else
allegedly that's the deep state we don't
know what it is it's not just the
bureaucracy it's a small number of
people allegedly who do that do we have
such a thing in India look in any
country you're going to have extra
democratic extra electoral centers of
power because the nation state system
and democracy all these things are very
new things and old systems persist in
some way or the other. So you're going
to have that but I don't think we can
call it India's deep state. So I would
not say that there is a deep state in
India the way you probably have in the
US. SKK welcome to the channel. Thank
you so much for becoming a member. I
appreciate that very much. Thank you.
Speed says, "Sir, how to establish deep
state? Love you, Sar." Okay. All right.
How to establish deep
state? Uh, you have to subwo a nation.
You have to hide everything you're
doing. You have to have access to
tremendous amounts of wealth and you to
deploy that wealth
to with the purpose of um of of
acquiring strategic assets which are
which are institutions,
people and so on. Very easy to say but
very difficult to do.
ICMBB says, "Is it possible that the US
used the IRA against the
UK?" Oh no, you can't say such things.
How can you say such things? That is
blasphemy. That's
taboo. Isn't it funny? The IRA was such
a thorn in the flesh of the UK when for
decades when it it was at the peak of
its uh activities when Margaret Thatcher
was the prime minister. the iron lady
who stood up to the
US and the moment the lap dog Tony Blair
comes to power the
IRA puts down its
weapons. What can I
say? Coincidence? Do you have
coincidences in
geopolitics? Saitar says, "Do you think
hydrogen cars will replace electric cars
in India within the next 10 years? How
much sustainable are these hydrogen
cars?
could happen. I think the government has
this initiative
uh of using uh of of of uh you know
using hydrogen vehicles of making
hydrogen powered vehicles mainstream in
India. I think it's a good initiative.
The only byproduct or waste product of
hydrogen combustion is water
vapor. And if you're talking about
hydrogen fuel cells, then that's a
different technology. Um, so will
hydrogen cars replace electric cars in
the next 10 years? I think hydrogen cars
could become hydrogen powered cars could
become a significant
uh sign could could represent a
significant percentage maybe 10 20 30%
of vehicles in India. It's possible. I
don't think they will completely replace
electric cars unless uh we develop some
groundbreaking technology and become a
world leader in that technology. Uh how
sustainable are hydrogen cars? Um it
depends on if it's fuel cell technology
which has hydrogen. I don't remember how
it really works. I had studied that when
I was a kid. Uh but if you're talking
about hydrogen
combustion, well that's what you have in
rockets essentially.
Um hydrogen combustion means you burn
hydrogen with oxygen to form form form
water vapor essentially. How
sustainable? I think it could be super
sustainable if you get it right, if you
get the technology
right. Adme says, "What if India was US
ally after 1947 and weak USSR?" What if
India was a US ally after 1947? Well, it
depends. It would have gone two ways. If
we played the Wasal game, we would have
become a complete US
vasal. Um, and the US would have
leveraged us against the USSR as well as
China. And then maybe China would not
have become a big thing because they had
India. So if India became a complete US
vasal then maybe China's rise would
never have happened. India would have
risen in its place. But India would have
been significantly compromised in
various ways because India is a US
facile. But if India is a US ally
without becoming a puppet or a
vasal then India could have done really
well potentially as long as India did
not come in the way of the US interests
in the cold war and India became a
manufacturing hub for the for the US
India could have
thrived really
well. Um yeah so it would all depend on
the leadership. It all boils down to
leadership always. So India could
possibly have done well with the right
leadership if India had chosen to become
an American ally. Jugen says, "What's
your views on USS space force? Are they
planning to use to place nuclear weapons
in space and launch from
there?" We don't know what the plans
are, but they have a space force. And by
the
way, the Americans have tested nuclear
weapons in space before. Uh let me show
you. Let's let's Google this
together.
Um US nuclear test in space. It was
called Starship something starfish
prime. They conducted nuclear tests in
space the Americans. Okay. And you can
read all about it. Uh so it's not like
it's some new thing deployment of
nuclear weapons in space. It's an old
idea. It's why the space race started
after the Russians placed Sputnik in
orbit in 1957. The
Americans, yeah, they were in a state of
panic. We have to catch up otherwise
we'll have nuclear weapons orbiting
above us. So, it's not a new thing. It's
possible that they may secretly be
planning to place whatever in space.
It's possible for
sure. Vic Post says, "I live in the US,
but I'm worried about cultural
abraheimization of India." Like Chanaki
said, we can only protect ourselves. um
until we protect our culture but the
west imposes conversions on India. You
are right um cultural abraimization is a
very big uh threat that India is facing.
The west imposes conversions on India.
There are industrial scale Christian
conversions that have happened in the
past in India's far east. Most of the
states of Nagaland Misoram have been
completely Christianized. Mizoram
completely gone. Nagaland also to a very
large extent. All the beautiful
indigenous culture wiped out. Now
they're doing it to
Banipur. It's also happening in Arunach
Pradesh. All of this happened during Mr.
Neu's time. Right? And now you have this
being deployed unleashed on the
remaining parts of India. One hears
there are tens of thousands of people
converting to Christianity every day
apparently in Punjab. They're targeting
the tribal belts of India. the people
who have been who whose whose ancestors
were horribly impoverished by the
British. So they're targeting the the
most vulnerable uh sections of society.
It's happening in to a large extent to a
significant extent in uh in other parts
also in in southern India and so on. And
we are allowing this to happen.
So I don't know what it is and why it's
happening and why it's being allowed but
this is an assault on Indian
civilization and
culture. Um and this should be banned
actually this is this is you know
industrial scale demographic
re-engineering that the west is
doing. So I think it's it's incumbent on
the Indian government to do something
about this but your worries are very
well founded. It's happening in real
time and it's terrible.
Noil Sony, first of all, thank you very
much. I hope fully GOI seeks your advice
before before your 999th video. Maybe
they will. Look, even if they're
listening and they implement something,
I'm happy with it. Yeah. So, anyway,
thank you so much, sir. Thank you. Neil
says, "Is the environmental crisis real
or exaggerated?" Look, much of it is
real. Climate change is real. Some of it
is a natural thing. Some of it is human
mediated, human-caused. The billions of
tons of plastic in the ocean are real.
Microplastics everywhere are real and so
on. So much of it is real. You can't say
it's
exaggerated, but there's nothing most
likely anybody can do about it. That's a
sad thing. Barav says, "Does Ukraine
want to deliberately escalate? If yes,
would it succeed? Is the IT job market
in India going to suffer?" Ukraine has
deliberately escalated. what they did
yesterday, operation spiderweb or
whatever they call it, is a deliberate
escalation and they know that Russia
will then retaliate. Russia has no no
option but to
retaliate. So Ukraine has deliberately
chosen the path of escalation. I mean
you can't you can't blame them because
they're in a war with Russia. Uh but
will they succeed? What what what is su
success from Ukraine's perspective?
Ukraine has two options. either you
completely defeat Russia, inflict a
comprehensive and complete military
defeat on Russia or end the war. Do you
think Ukraine is in a position to
comprehensively defeat Russia? It's not.
So, it's not going to
succeed. Is the IT job market in India
going to suffer? It's going to suffer
because of AI, not because of the
Ukraine war. AI will take over
everything. Rishab Yadav says, I want to
serve our nation. I'm 23. bureaucracy
interested in bureaucracy law and also
armed forces. I am disheartened because
honest officers are often sidelined in
their fields what to
do. Such is the system in
India. It's it's what it is. Like I've
said many times, India needs to at some
point in time launch a war against
corruption because then honest people
because of the system honest people get
disheartened and and the crooked people
allegedly they thrive. It's
terrible. So the question is what can
you do
sir? Bureaucracy I think you should stay
away from it.
law law also can be really disenchanting
once you see how things are
done. Yeah. Armed forces I think armed
forces it's a different story. I don't
think uh I think ar the armed forces
have a different set of standards better
set of standards than the bureaucracy
the law and all that all that. So I
think if you want to serve the nation
and you want honest people around you I
would say go to the armed forces. I will
not guarantee that everybody will be
honest. Okay. there's always some
problems over or the other but overall I
think the armed forces have much higher
standards than than the other uh sectors
of services. So I would say if you want
to remain honest if you don't want to
partake in
corruption and you want to serve the
country I think the armed forces are the
best way to do it. Okay sir all the best
all the best. Lalit Adita says UK is
preparing for war with the tiny 91k
British army against Russia. Also her
thoughts on recent drone attack by
Ukraine and
Russia. The UK is a nation with an with
an inflated sense of
self-importance. The UK was relegated to
the position to the status of a third
rate world power in 1956 after the
debacle of the Suis crisis in which the
US publicly humiliated the UK.
But they still have these delusions of
grandeur. So they think that by by by a
war of words they can defeat
Russia by posturing that we we will do
this and we'll do that. It's it's it's
it's a has been
nation and they will soon become the
Islamic Republic of whatever. So let's
not worry about them. The recent drone
attack on on Russia by Ukraine is a
major escalation and there's going to be
serious consequences in the next days
and
weeks. Anish says, "Is virtual Bible
school kids camp or conversion school?"
Yes, it is.
Yes. TJ 6789 says, "I found that Hiro
and Hiroshma and Nagasaki are not
radioactive as the bombs exploded 500
meters in the air. Will Russia or India
apply the strategy when the time comes?
I hope. Nobody ever detonates a nuclear
weapon in the future. I hope
so. And if you want to use nuclear
weapons, you don't if you are in a
situation where you are forced to use
nuclear weapons, uh you will use them to
the best of your
ability. So I don't know what kind of
weapons
uh we have. Do we have proximity fuses
or do we have impact fuses? I'm not sure
how it works, what our systems are like.
Uh but we're not going to worry about
what's going to happen 50 100 years down
the
line. When you when you are in a
position where you are forced to use
nuclear weapons, it's probably a matter
of survival or or extinction. At that
point in time, you don't think about
what will be the situation in the place
where the bomb explodes 100 years down
the line. You don't worry about that. Uh
so yeah, that's not a
consideration ever.
Okay, I will take this last question
today and that's it for today. Paras
Vidi says, "What kind of corruption
India has in education and health? Will
India ever be able to grow even with the
best government that we have till
now?" Look, education and health are
very different sectors in
education. Uh so all all kinds of
issues. Let's say you are doing a PhD.
Okay, it's very easy to get a fake PhD
none allegedly. It's very easy to get
somebody write your thesis for you
allegedly. Okay, that's a very easy and
you can allegedly buy degrees
allegedly. That's corruption in
education. And then
um there's also corruption in paper
publication and all that. There are all
these fake journals, this predatory
journals that uh will allow you to
publish any kind of research paper
without it being peer- reviewed for a
price. So that's corruption and so many
more things. I mean I can go on and on
about education in health.
I can't think of case studies or you use
cases for health corruption or examples
of health corruption but I'm sure uh
it's there as well. I think allegedly
every sector allegedly in India
allegedly has corruption right so it's
what it is uh will India ever be able to
grow even with the best government we
have till now you know India is growing
at six seven whatever% per year despite
all the
problems imagine if we remove the
problems what will happen India will I
promise you grow at 15% a
year uh so India will keep growing
despite all the problems but hopefully
the government does something about
corruption then India will be totally
unleashed
unshackled and that's what I would love
to see. All right my friends that's the
end of today's live
stream. All right. Uh is this okay?
Okay. So one last question I will take.
Major restoration was a two-edged
double-edged sword. Missionaries
destroyed culture plaza destroyed
economy. The plaza accords. Yes. Also
did US nuke Japan even though they
surrendered evil. So the major
resolution was a double-edged sword. It
made Japan a modern nation. It destroyed
Japan's culture. They tried to destroy
Buddhism and eradicate Buddhism from
from Japan. And the problem it caused is
that Japan became kind of culturally
rootless because of the major
restoration. Japan lost touch with its
cultural roots. If Japan had remained a
Buddhist nation, if the Japan Imperial
Army had remained rooted in Buddhist
Dharmic values, they would never have
done the things they did. But then they
would not have been able to conquer so
much. So yeah, you're right. It's a
double-edged sword. Missionaries
destroyed culture. There is a missionary
influence in Japan today, unfortunately.
Sadly. Yeah. And South Korea is
destroyed by missionaries and the Plaza
Accords destroyed the economy. You're
right. Uh did the US nuke Japan even
though they surrendered? What what one
learns in history books is that the
Japanese surrendered because they were
nuked twice. Until then, they were not
ready to surrender. So So all right. Uh
thank you everybody for all your
questions. I'm going to end the live
stream over here today and I will see
you tomorrow in two live streams. The
first one is the Indian interest which
returns after a gap of more than two
years and immediately after that there
will be another episode of ask. Thank
you so much for your questions, for your
viewership, and I will see you very soon
in the next live stream. Keep asking
questions, keep raising your standards.
Thank you very much. Bye-bye.